{
  "duration": "15",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "1",
      "question": "Everything in React is a ........................",
      "options": ["Module", "Component", "Package", "Class"],
      "correctOption": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "2",
      "question": "What of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
      "options": [
        "Original DOM",
        "Virtual DOM",
        "Both A and B",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "3",
      "question": "How many numbers of elements a valid react component can return?",
      "options": ["1", "2", "4", "5"],
      "correctOption": 1
    },
    {
      "id": "4",
      "question": "What are the two ways to handle data in React?",
      "options": [
        "State & Props",
        "Services & Components",
        "State & Services",
        "State & Component"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1
    },
    {
      "id": "5",
      "question": "Which of the following is used to pass data to a component from outside in React.js?",
      "options": ["SetState", "Render with arguments", "Props", "PropTypes"],
      "correctOption": 3
    },
    {
      "id": "6",
      "question": "Which of the following function is used to change the state of the React.js component?",
      "options": [
        "this.setState",
        "this.setChangeState",
        "this.State{}",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1
    },
    {
      "id": "7",
      "question": "React is ........................",
      "options": [
        "Component based",
        "Module based",
        "Both of above",
        "None of above"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1
    },
    {
      "id": "8",
      "question": "JSX allows us to write HTML elements in JavaScript and place them in the DOM without any?",
      "options": [
        "createElement",
        "appendChild",
        "getElementById",
        "Both A and B"
      ],
      "correctOption": 4
    },
    {
      "id": "9",
      "question": "Which of the following keyword is used to create a class inheritance?",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correctOption": 1
    },
    {
      "id": "10",
      "question": "What is a state in React?",
      "options": [
        "A permanent storage",
        "Internal storage of the component",
        "External storage of the component",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "11",
      "question": "In which of the following directory React.js components are saved?",
      "options": [
        "Inside the src/components/",
        "Inside the vendor/components/",
        "Inside the external/components/",
        "Inside the vendor/"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1
    },
    {
      "id": "12",
      "question": "What is true for the keys given to a list of elements in React?",
      "options": [
        "Unique in the DOM",
        "Unique among the siblings only",
        "Do not require to be unique",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "13",
      "question": "Which of the following method refers to the parent class in React.js?",
      "options": ["inherits()", "self()", "super()", "this()"],
      "correctOption": 3
    },
    {
      "id": "14",
      "question": "What does ES6 stand for?",
      "options": [
        "ECMAScript 6",
        "ECMA 6",
        "ECMAJavaScript 6",
        "EJavaScript 6"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1
    },
    {
      "id": "15",
      "question": "What is the use of the create-react-app command in the React.js application?",
      "options": [
        "It is used to update a React app.",
        "It is used to create a new React app.",
        "It is used to install dependencies.",
        "None of the above."
      ],
      "correctOption": 2
    }
  ]
}
